# **TRAVISBURCH**

#### FRONT-END **DEVELOPMENT**

**EMAIL** travisb.burch@gmail.com **PHONE** 704.692.1484 **GIT** github.com/tburch5387

#### ABOUT ME

I'm a front-end developer and web designer making a transition in my career after 10+ years in customer facing roles in the tourism industry. These experiences have developed my ability to read between the lines and understand what the client is actually looking for, even when they might not know the right question to ask. I am a tenacious google searcher and I love to learn new things and take on new challenges.

#### **SKILLSET**

HTML
CSS
JAVASCRIPT - NOVICE
PHOTOSHOP
ILLUSTRATOR
WORDPRESS ADMIN
MAC OS
WINDOWS
GITHUB
MAILCHIMP
JAVA - BASIC UNDERSTANDING
SQL - BASIC UNDERSTANDING
CUSTOMER SERVICE

#### **EDUCATION**

Javascript)

**MANAGEMENT** 

FURMAN UNIVERSITY (2009)
Bachelor of Arts
DREXEL UNIVERSITY (2011)
Digital Media and Design Coursework
GARDNER-WEBB UNIVERISTY (2015)
MBA - Hospitality and Tourism
TECH TALENT SOUTH (2018/2019)
Code Immersion (HTML/CSS/SQL/Java)
Front End Development (HTML/CSS/

WES BOS Beginner Javascript

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### US NATIONAL WHITEWATER CENTER

Guest Services Director (2015-2018)

- Manage and facilitate training of a team of up to 50 seasonal, hourly staff
- Oversee and manage all day to day operations of the Guest Services Department
- Address and resolve conflicts as they arise, seeking to find a mutually beneficial solution
- Maintain web page via Wordpress CMS

#### Race Director (2019-present)

- Plan, organize and execute all aspects of competitive events, including trail and bike races, climbing competitions and paddling events
- Manage a team of volunteers and staff to execute events at a high level and exceed customer expectations
- Code HTML emails in Mailchimp as needed for event notifications
- Design and build online order forms through Formsite

### Software Support (2019-present)

- Support primary sales point software (Siriusware) through troubleshooting and liaising with IT and Siriusware Technical support
- Worked with a new ecommerce vendor to set up an integration with Siriusware

#### GARDNER-WEBB UNIVERSITY/SODEXO

#### Catering Manager (2014-2015)

Manage, plan and oversee execution of all catering for campus events.

#### Retail Manager (2013)

- Oversee a staff of 25+ in a fast-paced food service environment across four concepts.
- Create and advertise specials and promotions for all concepts, including design, marketing and execution.

#### **Event Coordinator** (2012)

Schedule and organize event calendar and provide on-site management for events.

## MOUNTAIN SKY GUEST RANCH

Guest Services Specialist and Hiking Guide (2010-2011)